Guide to the E. A. Shaw & Company Records 1932-1956
Shaw, E. A. & Company Records
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
E. A. Shaw & Company Records, 1932-1956
6615
E. A. Shaw & Company
0.2 linear ft.
Correspondence.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Business records, 1932-1956, most from the Boston office & centering on information about ramie. Includes correspondence, all concerning ramie; some letters discuss decortication & degumming of the fibers. Also a file of information about ramie, and folders of samples of ramie twine, some of which was made in Switzerland & tested by the Plymouth Cordage Co.
0.25 cubic feet
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
E.A. Shaw & Co., cotton merchants & raw materials dealers with offices in Los Angeles and Boston.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection mostly from the Boston office and centering on information about ramie, a fiber obtained from the bark of the ramie plant. Includes correspondence, 1932-1933, 1948-1949, and 1954, all concerning ramie; some letters discuss decortication and degumming of the fibers. Also includes a file of information, 1956, about ramie; and folders of samples of ramie twine, including some made in Switzerland and tested by the Plymouth Cordage Co.
PROVENANCE:
American Textile History Museum Collection, gift of Gordon Shaw.
SUBJECTS
Names:
E. A. Shaw & Company; Plymouth Cordage Company.
Subjects:
Business records; Cotton trade; Plant fiber industry; Ramie; Ramie industry; Textile industry; Other natural fibers; Textile raw materials
Geographic Subjects:
Boston (Mass.); Los Angeles (Calif.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
CONTAINER LIST
- Sample No. 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Sample No. 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sample No. 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Sample No. 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sample No. 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Sample No. 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sample No. 7 & 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Ramie" - Harry Stone (Agent) Letters, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Ramie" - Harry Stone (Agent) -- Letter + notes, 1949, w/samples of Ramie (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Ramie" - Harry Stone (Agent) - Letters, w/sample, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Ramie" - Ramie rope samples, made in Switzerland, tested by Plymouth Cordase Co., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Ramie", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)